Guide to the Victor F. Germack and Lori Shepard Germack Collection of Photographs of Indians of North America
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographic Prints, Series IV; 2.4; (7 boxes)
  - Unidentified Photographers
    - Studio Portrait of Six American Indian Men and an American Indian Girl, circa 1890 (Box 23, Folder 1046)
    - Multnomah Falls, Oregon, circa 1883-1890 (Box 7, Folder 1047-1049)
    - Waterfall and Pool in a Canyon, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1050)
    - Copy Photograph of a Painting of Mount Rainier, Seattle, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1051)
    - Building with Six Stories, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1052)
    - American Indian Man Wearing a Fur Hat and Bone Ornaments, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1053)
    - Elderly American Indian Man, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1054)
    - Group of American Indians, including Three Men, Two Woman, and Two Young Girls, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1055)
    - Three American Indian Men Posed Standing in Front of a Tipi, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1056)
    - American Indian Man, Identified as an Indian Priest, Posed Standing in Front of a Tipi, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1057)
    - Copy Photograph of a Painting of Sitting Bull (Thatháŋka Íyotake), a Hunkpapa Indian Man, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1058)
      Based on an original photograph created by Orlando Scott Goff circa 1880.
    - Copy Photograph of Black Crow (Kangi Sapa, Kangi-Sha-Pa, or Kan-Gah-Sa-Pah), Brulé Indian Man, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1059)
    - American Indian Man with a Bow and Arrow, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1060)
    - American Indian Man, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1061)
    - African American Man, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1062)
    - American Indian Man, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1063)
    - Group of American Indian Children, Women, and Men at the Foot of a Totem Pole and in Front of Wooden Buildings, Probably Alaska or British Columbia, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1064)
    - Two American Indian Men in Front of Two Totem Poles and a Wooden Building, Probably Alaska or British Columbia, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 1065)
    - American Indian Man, Possible an Ojibwa Indian Man, Posed Standing and Holding a Rifle in Front of a Birch Bark Tipi, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1066)
    - Log Cabin with Two European American Women Sitting in Chairs and a European American Man in a Hammock, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1067)
    - American Indian Man, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1068)
    - Five American Indian Men and an American Indian Woman, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1069)
    - Two American Indian Men, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1070)
    - American Indian Infant in a Cradleboard, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1071)
    - Three American Indian Men; One Man Wears a Indian Police Badge, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1072)
    - Interior of a Large Group of Salish Indians at a Council Meeting at the Flathead Reservation, Montana, circa 1900 (Box 7, Folder 1073)
    - Two American Indian Men and an American Indian Woman Posed Sitting and Eating in Front of a Birch Bark Tipi and Painted Background, circa 1900 (Box 7, Folder 1074)
    - American Indian Man Posed Kneeling by a Stream, circa 1930 (Box 7, Folder 1075)
    - Julián Martinez (Pocano or Coming of the Spirits), Pueblo Indian Painter and Pottery Designer at the San Ildefonso Pueblo in New Mexico, as well as Husband of Potter Maria Martinez, circa 1930 (Box 7, Folder 1076)
- Photograph Albums and Photographically Illustrated Volumes, 1875-circa 1969; Series V; 1.46; (8 boxes)
  Associated Materials: An additional album of cartes-de-visite can also be found in Series II. Card Photographs.
  Series V is arranged chronologically.
  This series consists of photograph albums and photographically illustrated volumes that include images of American Indians and the Trans-Mississippi West.
  - Photograph Album of Cabinet Photographs by William Stinson Soule Compiled by Louis Root Spencer, 1875 (Box 8)
    Louis Root Spencer (1854-1876) was born in Connecticut, the son of Calvin Spencer (1813-1866) and Clarissa M. Root (1820-1899). Spencer served as a paymaster's clerk with the United States Army. On May 22, 1876, robbers shot him near Eureka, California, during a holdup, and he died of his wounds after an amputation of an arm.
    Formerly owned by Nelson Case Taintor (Yale 1909). Louis Root Spencer was his maternal uncle.
    An album compiled by Louis R. Spencer comprised of cabinet photographs created by William Stinson Soule that depict American Indian men and women in the vicinity of Fort Sill, Indian Territory. Groups include Arapaho Indians, Caddo Indians, Cheyenne Indians, Comanche Indians, Kiowa Apache, Kiowa Indians, and Wichita Indians.
    Images of Arapaho Indians in 1867 include portraits of Bird Chief, Little Raven, Powder Face, and Shibonester or Shib-O-Nes-Ter, as well as a view of the camp of Cut Hair.
    A sole portrait of a Caddo Indian depicts Chief George Washington in 1867.
    The album includes images of Kiowa Indians from 1867 to 1872. Portraits created in 1867 include Big Bow (Zepko-Ette), Salose or Sa-Lo-So (Son of White Bear), Tar-Lo, Tibone (Tau-Ankia, Son of Lone Wolf), Trailing the Enemy (To-Me-Ath-To or Eonah-Pah) and his Wife, White Bear (Satanta), and Woman's Heart (Manyi-Ten), as well as a man identified as possibly Standing-Sweat-House (Tape-day-ah). A 1868 portrait depicts Kicking Bird (Tene-Angpote). Portraits created in 1870 include Big Tree (Ado-Eette), Lone Wolf (Guipago), Not Afraid or Not Afraid of Any Indian (Ka-Ati-Wertz-Ama-Na), the sister of Chief Big Tree, Stumbling Bear (Set-Imkia), and White Horse (Tsen-T-Ainte). A portrait created in 1872 depicts Sun Boy. Other images of Kiowa Indians include an unidentified man and unidentified women, as well as a view of a Kiowa Indian camp with tipis, probably the camp of Lone Wolf or Kicking Bear.
    Images of Wichita Indians include a portrait of Nawatry, a Wichita Indian Woman, as well as portraits of unidentified women. There is also a view of a Wichita Indian camp with children.
    Images of Comanche Indians in 1867 include portraits of Grey Leggings (Asa-To-Yet or Esa-Ton-Yett), Hand Shaker (Mow-Way), Heap Wolves, Horse Back (Ta-Her-Ye-Qua-Hip), Otter Belt, Son of Horse Back, and Standing-Sweat-House (Tape-day-ah), as well as portraits of Comanche Indian women, Chi-Wek-Kiethe and her sister, Looking For Something Good (Cha-Wa-Ke). There is also a view of the Comanche Indian camp of Hand Shaker (Mow-Way).
    Images of Cheyenne Indians include a portrait of Cheyenne Indian Women Sauke and Hat-Py or Hathy in 1867, and a Cheyenne Indian camp in 1869 that includes scout and interpreter Horace Pope Jones (1829-1901).
    Portrait of Kiowa Apache Indians in 1867 include Pacer and his son, as well as Black Hawk.
    A portrait in the album depicts a European American boy allegedly held captive by American Indians.
  - William Henry Jackson, Colorado (Denver: W. H. Jackson), 1882 (Box 9)
    Distributed Benjamin Austin Taft in Silverton, Colorado.
    Volume of sixteen photographs created by William Henry Jackson mounted on twelve boards folded in concertina style, which depict views of Colorado, 1882.
    The sequence of images in the volume includes: Durango, Colorado (No. 3214); Cañon of the Rio Las Animas (No. 3260); Needle Mountains from Animas Cañon (No. 2885); Deer Park Cascade, Animas Cañon (No. 3258); Elk Park, Animas Cañon (No. 3257); Silverton (No. 3256); Silverton (No. 3265); and Baker's Park (No. 3243), and then followed by the next sequence of images that represent half stereograph views: Cunningham Gulch, Baker's Park (No. 3131); A Mountain Trail (No. 3132); Silverton from the Cascade (No. 3152); Needle Mountains from Baker's Park (No. 3153); Cascade Below Silverton (No. 3154); Cascade Below Silverton (No. 3155); Cascade Near Elk Park, Animas Cañon (No. 3156); and Deer Park Cascade, Animas Cañon (No. 3156).
  - Album of Seattle, Snoqualmie Hop Ranch, and Logging Operations in Washington with Photographs by John P. Soule, 1890-1893 (Box 10)
    The album of photographs created by professional photographer John P. Soule, circa 1890-1893, that document the reconstruction of Seattle, Washington, after the Great Fire of 1889, as well as a hops farm and logging operations in northwestern Washington.
    Images of Seattle include views of Front Street, coal bunkers, and lumber mills, as well as a camp of American Indian hop pickers on the waterfront. Identified buildings and city blocks include Burke Building, Chamber of Commerce Building, Harrisburg Block, Hotel Rainier, John Cort's Standard Theatre, King County Courthouse, Occidental Hotel, Olympic Block, and Pioneer Building, as well as the powerhouse for cable cars on the Union Trunk Line.
    Images of ships in the vicinity of Seattle include the United States Revenue Cutter Bear and United States Cruiser Charleston, as well as the Mary L. Burrill loading the first shipment wheat on November 3, 1890, from the grain terminal in West Seattle.
    A group of images document American Indian hop pickers at the Snoqualmie Hop Ranch in Snoqualmie, Washington, as well as a ferry at the farm.
    Photographs of logging operations include the logging camp of John Edgecomb in Snohomish County and logging by the Huron Lumber Company in Bothell, as well as ships loading lumber at Port Blakeley.
  - Album of Trip from Nebraska to Virginia, 1893 (Box 11)
    An album by an unidentified compiler. Photographs created by professional photographers document sites along a journey from Omaha, Nebraska through Colorado, Utah, California, New Mexico, Missouri, Georgia, South Carolina, to Virginia, January 13 to March 17, 1893. The compiler then traveled from New York on April 5 to Liverpool on April 13 in the saloon class aboard the SS Teutonic.
    Images of Omaha, Nebraska, visited January 13, include the Bee Building, Douglas County Courthouse, Omaha City Hall, and Paxton Hotel.
    Images of Colorado, visited January 18-24, include views of Denver, Garden of the Gods, and Colorado Springs. Images of Denver include Arapahoe County Court House, Colorado State Capitol, Denver High School, Equitable Building, and St. John's Episcopal Cathedral. Images of Garden of the Gods and Colorado Springs include photographs by William Edward Hook that depict rock outcroppings and waterfalls, as well as an image of the summit of Pike's Peak with the Army Signal Station and a locomotive from the Manitou and Pike's Peak Railway.
    Images of Salt Lake City, Utah, visited January 25, include the gravesite of Brigham Young, the Tabernacle and Temple in Salt Lake City, and the Garfield Beach and Pavilion on the Great Salt Lake.
    Images of California, visited January 27 to February 14, include views of San Francisco, Monterey, and Santa Cruz by Isaiah West Taber. Photographs of San Francisco include Chinatown, Golden Gate Park, Golden Gate, and Goat Island, as well as Sutro Heights and Cliff House, including adjacent Seal Rocks. Several images document Hotel del Monte in Monterey, including the Arizona Garden. Photographs of Santa Cruz depict coast redwood trees, including Grizzly Giant. Other images of sites in California include the ranch of Joel Parker Whitney in Rocklin, as well as views of sites in Los Angeles by C.C. Pierce & Co., including the avenue of palms at the homestead of Charles A. Longstreet.
    Images of New Mexico, visited February 17, include photographs by Dana B. Chase of sites in Santa Fe, including the San Miguel Church and the Palace of the Governors, as well as portraits of American Indians, including Signor Peso, the chief of the scouts who captured Geronimo. Other portraits of American Indians attributed to Joseph Parker include Hopi Indians, Laguna Indians, Mojave Indians, and Navajo Indians.
    Images of Missouri, visited February 19 to March 2, include overviews of Kansas City and its stockyards, as well as the Saint Louis School and Museum of Fine Arts and Eads Bridge in Saint Louis.
    Images of Atlanta, Georgia, visited March 7-12, include views of Grant Park and the Georgia State Capitol.
    Photographs of South Carolina, visited March 12-17, include the South Carolina Lunatic Asylum in Columbia, as well as Saint Michael's Episcopal Church and residences on the Battery in Charleston.
    Images of Richmond, Virginia, visited March 17, include Libby Prison, Old Stone House, and St. Paul's Episcopal Church.
  - Album of American Indians Compiled by Patrick Cavanaugh Smith, 1902 (Box 12)
    Patrick Cavanaugh Smith (1886-1973) was a painter and artist in Louisville, Kentucky.
    An album compiled by Patrick Cavanaugh Smith in 1902 of photographs and photomechanical prints that depict American Indians. The album includes twenty-six photographs created by John F. Byrnes and Company that depict unidentified performers in Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show, as well as two chromolithographic portraits of performers by William M. Rau. The album also includes thirty-two halftones of images of identified American Indians created by Frank Albert Rinehart and Adolph F. Muhr, 1898-1899.
    The album also includes eight copy photographs distributed by the Pioneer Roll Paper Co. that depict portraits of American Indians. Discrete portraits by William Stinson Soule originally created in 1867 include Comanche Indian men Grey Leggings (Asa-To-Yet or Esa-Ton-Yett), Horse Back (Ta-Her-Ye-Qua-Hip), and Tosh-A-Wah (misidentified as Turtle Dove or Co-U-Wa); Kiowa Indian men Big Bow (Zepko-Ette or Ate-te-leaf) and Woman's Heart (Manyi-Ten); and Arapaho Indian Man Little Raven. There is also a copy photograph of Not Afraid or Not Afraid of Any Indian (Ka-Ati-Wertz-Ama-Na), a Kiowa Indian Man, originally created by Soule in 1870. Another copy photograph depicts a portrait of Striker (Da-Ho or Ta-Ho), an Apache Indian man, created by William P. Bliss, circa 1867. An unidentified portrait of a European American man posed standing and wearing American Indian regalia.
  - Sample Album of Photographs of American Indians Created by Oxford & Dillhoff, 1902 May (Box 13)
    Sample photograph album of twenty-two mounted studio portrait photographs of American Indian performers in the Buffalo Bill Wild West Show created in May 1902 by the photographic studio of Oxford & Dillhoff in Brooklyn, New York.
    Identified individuals include William Fire Thunder (No.16568), Dreaming Bear (No.16571), Good Bird (No.16573), Mary Picket Pin (No.16580), Holy Bear (No.16585), Brings Plenty (No.16588), Iron White Man and his wife (No.16592), Iron White Man (No.16594), Henry Horse (No.16600), Two Bull (No.16603), Makes Good (No.16605), Sammy Long Bear (No.16609), Samuel American Horse (No.16613), Mrs. Samuel American Horse (No.16617), Come Last (No.16619), Charlie Picket Pin (No.16621), Conquering Bear (No.16625), Conquering Bear and White Coyote (No.16626), White Coyote (No.16631), Good Crow (No.16634), John Come After (No.16635), and Augustus Between Lodges (No.16636).
  - Rinehart's Prints of American Indians, circa 1969 (Box 14–15)
    The volumes may derive from a project by Royal Sutton, a former president of the Rinehart-Mardsen Studio in Omaha to reproduce the content of folio volumes originally created by George Marsden (1886-1966) of the Rinehart-Mardsen Studio with backing from the J. L. Brandeis and Sons Store. The original folio volumes were likely created for the world premiere of the film Union Pacific, which took place in Omaha on April 28, 1939, during a four-day celebration known as "Golden Spike Days," which celebrated the joining of the Central Pacific and Union Pacific railroads in 1869.
    Two octavo volumes, created circa 1969, each containing 65 electrophotographic prints that reproduce portraits of American Indians created by Frank A. Rinehart or his assistant Adolph F. Muhr of participants in the Indian Congress of the Trans-Mississippi and International Exposition, held in Omaha, Nebraska, between June 1 and October 31, 1898. A leaf containing identification, some with a brief biographical sketch, precede each print.
    The volumes are bound in buckskin with pyrographically inscribed titles, volume designations, and decorations on their covers, as well as boards comprised of thick leather with pyrographically decorated interiors. Nancy L. Hontz created the pyrographic decorations based on American Indian motifs.
- Photographic Transparencies, circa 1878-circa 1920; Series VI; 0.71; (1 box)
  Series VI is arranged by format: a stereographic transparency followed by lantern slides.
  This series consists of photographic material designed for viewing by transmitted light. This includes an example of a stereograph transparency and a group of lantern slides, which are photographic images on glass, intended for viewing by projection.
  - Stereograph Transparency
    - Ferrier père fils et Soulier, J. Levy Sr., Conseil d'Indiens à Shee-Pah-Lavy (New Mexico) (No.10379), circa 1878-1887 (Box 16, Folder 1077)
      The image depicts a group of Hopi Indians and buildings at Supawlavi (Shipaulovi) on Second Mesa, Arizona.
      Ferrier père fils et Soulier, J. Levy Sr. was a partnership between Claude-Marie Ferrier and his son, Jacques-Alexandre Ferrier, as well as Charles Soulier and J. Levy, 1878-1887.
  - Lantern Slides
    - Unidentified Photographer, Burial of Indian Police Killed in Sitting Bull Fight, Fort Yates, North Dakota (No.9461), 1890 December 17 (Box 16, Folder 1078)
    - Novelty Slides, Our Great West, circa 1910-circa 1920; (50 lantern slides) (Box 16, Folder 1079-1128)
      Incomplete set of lantern slides that depict sites in the Western United States. Images include views of Canyon de Chelly, Grand Canyon, Yellowstone National Park, and Yosemite National Park, as well as Garden of the Gods and Pikes Peak in Colorado.
      The slides do not have identifying captions or inscriptions.
      Extant lantern slides include No. 1, 12-14, 16-22, 24-27, 31, 33-40, 42-44, 49-50, 52-57, 57a, 58-71. There are also two transparencies numbered No. 70.
- Postcards, circa 1900-1978; Series VII; 1; (1 box)
  Series VII is organized into two subseries: Photographic Postcards and Photomechanical Postcards.
  This series consists of postcards.
  - Photographic Postcards
    Photographic postcards have on one side an image produced with light-sensitive materials directly on the card rather than photomechanical cards created on a printing press.
    Arranged alphabetically by photographer or studio followed by postcards made by unidentified creators.
    - Bates, Edward
      - Comanche Mother and Papoose; a Comanche Indian Woman with an Infant in a Cradleboard, circa 1915 (Box 17, Folder 1129)
    - Chapple, Charles John
      - Crow Indian Man and Child (No. A74), circa 1935 (Box 17, Folder 1130)
      - Crow Indians at Billings Fair, Montana (No. A79), circa 1935 (Box 17, Folder 1131)
    - Doubleday, Ralph R.
      - The Indian Ford of Yesteryear; American Indian Woman on Horseback with Two American Indian Children in a Travois, circa 1925 (Box 17, Folder 1132)
    - Hileman, Tomar Jacob
      - Chief Two Guns White Calf, Glacier National Park (No. 9524), circa 1927 (Box 17, Folder 1133)
    - Moorhouse, Thomas Leander "Lee"
      - Susan, Yakima Indian Klootchman (Mother) (No. 1116), circa 1900 (Box 17, Folder 1134)
    - Willis, Joseph Roy "J. R."
      - Antoine Montoya, San Domingo (No. 202), 1922-1926 (Box 17, Folder 1135)
    - Unidentified Photographer
      - European American Man and Woman Displaying a Line of Fish in Front of a European American Man Dressed in American Indian Regalia and a European American Group of Three Women, Two Men, and a Boy, in Mackinaw City, Michigan, circa 1900 (Box 17, Folder 1136)
      - William F. "Buffalo Bill" Cody and American Indians from his Wild West Show at the Monument to Chief Uncas at the Royal Mohegan Burial Ground, Norwich, Connecticut, 1907 July 2 (Box 17, Folder 1137)
      - Three Men, a Woman, and a Boy in Two Canoes in Hooker Tableau; Two Men Wearing American Indian Regalia, 1908 October 6 (Box 17, Folder 1138)
      - Group of Fourteen American Indian Women and Girls, as well as an American Indian Boy and Infant, All Wearing Regalia, circa 1910 (Box 17, Folder 1139)
      - Man Wearing American Indian Regalia on Horseback and Holding a United States Flag, circa 1910 (Box 17, Folder 1140)
      - American Indian Dancers, Probably in New Mexico, circa 1920 (Box 17, Folder 1141)
      - American Indian Man Wearing a Feather Headdress and Blanket, as well as Holding a Parfleche, circa 1930-1935 (Box 17, Folder 1142)
      - E-Yeh-Shure (Blue Corn) and Grandmother (No. 41), circa 1940 (Box 17, Folder 1143)
        Probably depicts Louise Abeita Chewiwi (Blue Corn, E-Yeh-Shure), a Native American writer and educator.
  - Photomechanical Postcards
    Postacrds bearing images printed in ink by a variety of mechanical transfer processes that reproduce photographs, rather than postcards created via light sensitive photographic processes.
    - A. C. Bosselman and Company
      - Geronimo, the Warrior (No. 6815), circa 1906 (Box 17, Folder 1144)
    - A. H. Company
      - Taos Girl with Olla, a Water Carrier, circa 1910 (Box 17, Folder 1145)
        Verso refers to another postcard: Cliff Dwellers (No. 1017).
    - A. Young and Company
      - Grand Parade of Blackfoot Indians (No. 158-2); Sihasapa Indians on Horseback, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1146)
      - The Sioux Dance (No. 158-3); Group of Dakota Indians from Behind, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1147)
      - Medicine Lodge, Blackfoot Indians (No. 158-4); Circle Camp of Sihasapa Indians, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1148)
      - Blood Squaws in War Dress (No. 158-6); Kootenai Indian Women on Horseback, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1149)
      - Chief Joe Healy and Braves (No. 158-8 and No. 648); Kootenai Indian Men, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1150-1151)
      - The Horn Society of Alberta Indians (No. 158-9); Kootenai Indian Men, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1152)
      - Old Time Piegan Squaw with Travois and Papoose (No. 158-10), 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1153)
    - Albertype Company
      - Geronimo, Apache Chief and United States Guard, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1154)
      - North House, Taos Pueblo, New Mexico, circa 1930 (Box 17, Folder 1155)
      - Indian Artist at Taos Pueblo, New Mexico, circa 1930 (Box 17, Folder 1156)
    - American Import Company
      - Indian Squaws, Chautauqua Grounds, Devils Lake, North Dakota (No. 871 and No. 68044), circa 1910 (Box 17, Folder 1157)
    - American Journal Examiner
      - The Historian; Painting of an American Indian Man Instructing an American Indian Boy, 1906 (Box 17, Folder 1158-1160)
    - Art Litho Company
      - Zuni Indians Drilling Shell Beads (No. 228), circa 1900 (Box 17, Folder 1161)
    - Barry Brothers
      - Indian War Dance (No. 7), circa 1905-1910 (Box 17, Folder 1162)
    - Beach, Henry S.
      - Drawing the Threads, Mexico, circa 1909 (Box 17, Folder 1163)
    - Brill, Charles
      - Chippewa Indian Fishermen Riding Out a Squall, circa 1978 (Box 17, Folder 1164)
        Postcard promotes Charles Brill's exhibition, "Indian and Free: Portrait of the Chippewa," at the American Indian Community House, New York City, August 15-October 31, 1978.
    - Chamberlain, John N.
      - Seminole Indians, Miami, Florida, circa 1905 (Box 17, Folder 1165)
    - Colourpicture Publishers
      - Indian Maid, circa 1979 (Box 17, Folder 1166)
        Photograph by Bob Taylor.
    - Daily Herald Company
      - Indian Scenes Near Everett, Washington (No. 103), circa 1905 (Box 17, Folder 1167)
    - Dean Color Service
      - Indian Village, Lake George, New York (No. 67373), circa 1950 (Box 17, Folder 1168)
        Original photograph by Richard K. Dean.
    - Detroit Photographic Company
      - James A. Garfield, Apache Indian (No. 5243), 1899 (Box 17, Folder 1169)